I’ve had enough...
Why’d the AC have to break
today of all days...?
Orio’s working like mad
to fix it for us...
Ugh. Feel like I can’t be bothered
to do anything...
Same for Navi.
So hot, so fed up...
It’s practically a sauna in there.
There couldn’t possibly be a bigger waste of time than—
Hey, hey, hey!
You’re slacking, Rising Voltteccers!
“Is this abnormal heat wave
an omen of a super ice age?!
“What mysteries await
once Ice-type Pokémon proliferate?!”
Now there’s a scoop!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Mr. Sohdayo?!
Yup! Sohdayo, in pursuit of
the unfabricated truth; that’s me!
It’s been a while, guys!
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Astonishing! Mega Rekkuuza and the Land of Mystery?!
A Pokémon Journalist?
Yeah. Mr. Sohdayo is a former member
of the Rising Voltteccers...
...and a globe-trotting reporter!
He’s even written
an article on us before.
The truth-seeking Pokémon Journalist,
Sohtim da Yotim! For short, Sohdayo!
And this is my partner, Sohnano!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
A truth-seeking Pokémon Journalist...
So cool!
Heh, gettin’ all excited...
Such a little kid.
You’re the little kid
for calling me one! Nyah-nyah!
Hmph.
Sohdayo’s just a deceitful dimwit.
Non, non!
There are countless truths
decried as deceitful!
Deception is a looking-glass
that reflects the truth, Molly.
Sohnano?
Is that right?
There’s not even a hint of truth
to be found in you!
Hey, hey...
Is that any way to speak to your senior?
By two days!
I still wish I could go back and change that.
Oh, that reminds me! You hear the rumors
of the Pokémon that can alter the past?!
No, I have not!
Same old routine with them...
I wonder if Mr. Sohdayo’s on the trail
of something strange again.
Wanna hear what, youngsters?
Huh?
N-Not...
Okay, okay! Say no more!
I’m here to gather material for a special feature
that’ll be in the next Occulture.
Occulture?!
Yes. I call it...
“Astonishing!
The Enigmatic Land of Mystery: Area Delta”!
Area Delta?
Area Delta,
said to be located south of here.
Shrouded amidst triangular rocks,
it’s said to be the entrance to another world.
And on the night of the full moon,
it’s the site of eerie cursed dances to repel intruders...
Anyone who still dares tread inside
receives a harsh welcome.
Assaults from rampaging rocks
and fierce gales,
as well as burns from blazing hellfire,
as one account has it...
And I’ve yet to mention
Area Delta’s greatest mystery...
A terrifying Pokémon
that drags intruders off to another world!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Wh-What Pokémon is it...?
The answer will knock you flat!
The Pokémon that is
legend among legends: Rekkuuza!
And it’s no ordinary Rekkuuza.
It’s eaten a meteor in the ozone layer,
taken in its energy, and Mega Evolved...
...into Mega Rekkuuza!
Mega Rekkuuza?!
Whoa! Amazing!
You serious?!
Oh, but we...
Of course!
I know all too well of your profound connection
with the black Rekkuuza.
Which is why I came here!
What do you mean?
Since you guys managed to
form a bond with the black Rekkuuza,
I thought you might be able to
get through to Mega Rekkuuza, too!
You’ll be able to delve into
the mysteries of Area Delta!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
Give it up, Sohdayo.
Stop involving the kids
in your dimwitted tales.
Aha, I hear you, Molly.
You want to come along too!
Huh?
Very well! I shall let you gaze into
the abyss of truth, like old times!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
How ridiculous.
Well, I’m feeling the heat less,
thanks to you.
Uhh...
Right now, we’re a little...
Say no more!
I know how you feel.
You all want to accompany me to Area Delta.
Sohnano!
That’s right!
Yeah, I wanna go with you!
Navi, too!
Huh?!
I admire Occulture, so getting to
tag along on research for it...
That’s a golden opportunity!
Please take us there!
Ooh! Girls with such a gleam
in their eyes!
Now there’s a fine sight to see!
Then, on the full moon’s night...
We depart at sunset!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
Me too, me too!
I’m gonna catch that Mega Rekkuuza for sure!
Navi wants to see it, too!
We’re leaving at night.
You won’t be awake then.
Navi will be awake!
I’m definitely, definitely going!
She didn’t manage to stay up, huh?
She said she was too excited
to nap during the day...
Heh! It’s a relief
not havin’ that loudmouth around!
The real loudmouth here’s you...
haaah... Ult.
Wow! Look, everyone!
Good omens ahead!
What?
The stars?
There’re green stars forming a triangle,
and small stars stretching out like whiskers, right?
That’s none other than the captivating
summer constellation: the Mega Rekkuustellation!
Mega Rekkuustellation
Mega Rekkuu... stellation?
Is that a thing?
I’ve never heard of it.
Naturally!
Because I made it up just now!
Shocking! When the Mega Rekkuustellation looms
in the southern sky, Mega Rekkuuza will show itself!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
And it will lead us to
another world in Area Delta!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Aw man, I’m itchin’ to go!
Just you wait, Mega Rekkuuza!
That’s the spirit, boy!
Yeah! I’ll do it!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
It’s a Bulbeat!
They talk with their friends
by flashing the lights on their rears.
Wow... It’s so pretty!
That Gamale’s going after
the Mitsuhoney’s honey!
Ooh, you’re right!
Somethin’ there!
It’s a Donkarasu
leading a flock of Yamikarasu.
This’ll make for a nice shot!
We’ve arrived, youngsters!
This is Area Delta!
This is...?
It looks like any old rocky place...
Look! A triangular rock!
Ooh, you’re right!
Well, I guess you could
call it triangular...
And those dead branches
form a triangle!
And if you connect them with that flat rock,
they form a triangle!
Sohnano!
That’s right!
W-Well... Maybe, I guess?
We’ve already intruded upon
the Land of Mystery: Area Delta.
Watch your step, youngsters.
Anything could happen.
Now, it’s time to bust out
my secret weapon!
Ta-daah!
Ooh! What’s that?!
Whoa, so cool!
Huh?
This is a device to lure out
Mega Rekkuuza!
You made that?
I bought it in an online auction!
Switch... on!
Nothing’s happening.
Wh-What?!
I-Is this...?
What is this?
The door to another world
has opened!
A-Another world?!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
A-Another world?!
This must be the cursed dance
held on full moon nights!
Everyone, watch out!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
No, hold on, those are...
Pippi!
Aww, how cute!
Pippi. Fairy Pokémon. Fairy type.
On nights with a full moon,
Pippi gather from places unknown and dance.
Bathing in the moonlight, they float.
Awesome! We get to watch a Pippi dance!
That’s an ultra-rare experience!
That looks fun!
Marvelous!
Pokémon in synchronized night dance!
As if enacting a ritual
to communicate with the moon!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
R-R...
What’s wrong, Roy?
Rocks!
Retreat!
Loudbone! Charm Voice!
Yamirami! Power Gem!
That was close.
But why did those rocks fall?
Area Delta itself
is repelling our intrusion.
Sohnano?
Is that right?
You serious?!
Masquernya! Magical Leaf!
Wanival! Aqua Cutter!
One more time!
Everyone! Flee into there!
Are we in the clear...?
Is this place...?
One... Two... Three...
The Triangular Room!
This is the deepest point
of Area Delta!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
It just looks like
some open space to me...
No, he could be right.
Huh?
The things Mr. Sohdayo told us
about Area Delta before we left...
Pippi may have been behind it,
but the cursed dance was Riolu...
Oh, the rampaging rocks!
And the fierce winds!
And the burn-y... whatever-it-was-fire!
Sohnano...
Everything Mr. Sohdayo said was true!
Exactly! We have gazed into
the abyss of the truth!
Truly, the truth is what we make it!
The greatest mystery
will soon be unveiled!
Mr. Sohdayo!
Huh?
Wha—?!
What the heck?!
Could this be...?
Here it comes!
The greatest mystery!
Mega Rekkuuza!
Huh?
We’re... floating?
What’s going on?
Wow, so many Pokémon!
Whoa, awesome!
It’s the guidance of
the Mega Rekkuuza!
It’s taken us to
some mysterious other world!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Whoa, what a shock!
Mega Rekkuuza returns!
Whoa, awesome!
It’s so rare,
I’m shocked all oveRishan!
Then I’ll take you on in battle!
Leave it to me!
I’ll catch you! Let’s go, Yamirami!
Draconic Masterstroke
is neaRunpappa!
That’s dangerous!
Yamirami got...!
Eek! Oh dear!
Wow! Was it hungry?
So a Mega Rekkuuza’s
favorite food is Yamirami?
This is the discovery of the century!
Wow, oh dear, oh dear!
Wow! Cool!
Yamirami...
Did you... gaze upon the truth?
Marvelous!
Mega Rekkuuza and Pokémon performing together!
The ultimate showtime!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Yay! Wanival, let’s get in on
the dancinGusokumusha!
They’re really grooving!
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
I have gazed upon the abyss of truth.
The charming, mysterious,
and mega-strongest.
Yamirami! Power Gem!
Whoa, what an upset!
Mega Rekkuuza went down
to one hit from Yamirami!
My, my, my, my, my, my?!
Wow, wow, wow!
As our unfabricated promise foretold...
Accept your capture!
Huh?
Just now, we were doing...
whaTairetsu?
What was that?
Th-That was...
An unmistakable
paranormal phenomenon!
We have wandered
into another world!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
What’s that...?
Of course... The Pippi’s dance!
Dance?
Look. They’re Wagging Fingers
while dancing.
Pippi’s Wag Finger activates
various different moves at random...
So maybe they used Eerie Light
or something?
Then that means we...
...were confused...
Hey! Where’s the Mega Rekkuuza?!
An Arbo...
An alternate-color one, at that!
Whoa, I’ve never seen one before!
They’re super rare!
Could that mean...
...this Arbo was the Mega Rekkuuza?
What?! You serious?!
What a mysterious,
wonderful, unusual experience!
My upcoming special feature’s
going to be superb!
Thank you, Area Delta!
Sohnano?
Is that right?
Everyone, look!
They updated with the new Occulture.
What about Mr. Sohdayo’s article?
Did he write about us?
That was that time Ult thought
he saw a Mega Rekkuuza, right?
Shut it! You were asleep!
Only cause you didn’t wake me up!
Aww, Navi wanted to go too...
“And so, having escaped
the cursed dance,
“we wandered into another world
by the guidance of the Mega Rekkuuza.
“The truth of the Land of Mystery,
Area Delta will now be revealed!”
Huh?!
There’s photos!
They’re all blurry!
“Unfortunately, some kind of interference
kept us from capturing the other world on film.
“But this interference
only proves it was real!
“We will continue to pursue the truth!”
Huh? But that...
...didn’t reveal any truth at all.
I told you.
He’s a deceitful dimwit.
Well, this is typical for Occulture...
B-But still, I saw the Pippi’s dance,
so I enjoyed it!
So jealous!
Navi wanted to see it, too!
Even if it was an illusion,
you met Mega Rekkuuza! Not fair!
Argh, but I wanted to catch it!
You even had the guidance of
the Mega Rekkuustellation hanging in the night sky.
It’s not something you can
expect to see every day.
Though it’d be incredible
if it really did show up.
That reminds me,
didn’t you tell us before, Molly?
When Sohnano says
“Sohnano!” with certainty...
Yeah. It means Sohdayo’s
telling the truth for once.
So, how did it respond to
the Mega Rekkuustellation?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Rekkuuza!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Rekkuuza
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Heavens Pokémon
Dragon
Flying
Air Lock
Apparently, eating something
is important for it to Mega Evolve,
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
but do you know what thing that is?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
A berry
A meteorite
Coal
B: A meteorite!
A meteorite
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
By eating a meteorite and storing the energy
in its body, it gains the ability to Mega Evolve!
Shooting stars!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Huh? Isn’t that...?
Next episode
What do I do?
Wanival and Dekanuchan can’t sleep!
Huh? Not one wink?
Next episode
If they nod off,
they wake up right away.
That sounds like trouble.
Sleep is very important, after all.
Who’re you?!
Next episode
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Wanival and Dekanuchan,
the Great Sleep Operation!
Everyone, eat well and sleep well!
Wanival and Dekanuchan,
the Great Sleep Operation!
Who are you, already?!